# Mahban Gholijafari

AMIRKABIR UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (TEHRAN POLYTECHNIC) | ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT

📞 (+98) 991-2793857 | 🖂 mahbangj@gmail.com | mahbangj@aut.ac.ir | 🕠 mahbangj | 🚺 mahban-jafari

# **Summary**

B.Sc. Electrical Engineering student at Amirkabir University of Technology, IRAN's Top-ranked University, with a 3.88 GPA. Passionate about Robotics. Worked as a researcher and IoT engineer, implementing multiple projects by MATLAB, having Electrical Circuits I and II courses teaching assistant experience for three semesters, and currently working on a Fuzzy-PID controller as a thesis project.

Research Interests: Machine Learning, Mathematics, Control, Robotics, Image Processing and Computer Vision, Digital Signal Processing

# **Education**

### **B.Sc. Electrical Engineering**

Tehran, Iran

May 2018 - May 2022

July 2014 - July 2018

AMIRKABIR UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (TEHRAN POLYTECHNIC)

- GPA: 3.88/4.0 (17.95/20)
- Field(s) of Study: Control Engineering
- Thesis: Construction and Control of a Three-Link Robot using a Fuzzy-PID Controller

### **High school Diploma in Mathematics and Physics**

Tehran, Iran

FARZANEGAN II (NATIONAL ORGANIZATION FOR DEVELOPMENT OF EXCEPTIONAL TALENT)

· GPA: 19.81/20

# **Teaching Experience**

### **Teaching Assistant**

AMIRKABIR UNIVERSITY

- Electric Circuits I, EE
- Lecturer: Dr. M. Khosravi
- · Spring 2022 Present

### **Teaching Assistant**

AMIRKABIR UNIVERSITY

- Electric Circuits II, EE
- Lecturer: Dr. M. Karrari
- Fall 2021 Present

# Work & Volunteer Experience \_\_\_\_

**IoT Engineer** Tehran, Iran

TECNIKAN May 2022 - October 2022

• Smart Home

- Obtained skills: C(programming language), C++, MySQL, ATmelAVR, Linux
- Simple template of handsfree-drawer using stepper motor and ATmega16: **Github**

### **Member of the Innovation Center at Electrical Engineering Department**

SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY PARK - AMIRKABIR UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

April 2022 - Present

April 2022 - Present

· Executive team member

# Member of Student Committee

Tehran, Iran

Tehran, Iran

ICROM - K. N. Toosi University of Technology

August 2022 - Present

- Executive team member
- The 10<sup>th</sup> RSI international conference on robotics and mechatronics

### Researcher (Internship)

Tehran Iran

July 2022 - Present

July 2021 - September 2021

Amirkabir University of Technology

Tank gauging using fiber optic technology

• Fiber optic sensors have been around for more than thirty years and have been successfully implemented in different areas like strain monitoring, inertial navigation, chemical substance detecting, and underwater acoustic sensing. These sensors have many characteristic advantages such as their contact with explosive materials or in fire-hazardous environments, small size and weight, electrical insulation, electromagnetic interference resistance, and prompt response.

# Skills

MATLAB Control System Toolbox, Signal Processing Toolbox, Simscape Multibody, App Designer, Fuzzy Logic Toolbox

C & C++ AVR Microcontroller, ARM Microcontroller, STM32CubeMX, Linux, Arduino, QT

**Python** Jupyter Notebooks, NumPy, TensorFlow, Matplotlib, Tkinter

**Robotics** Altium Designer, SOLIDWORKS, Code Vision AVR, PLC Ladder Logic, SIMATIC STEP 7, Proteus

Other Skills GitHub, Microsoft Office , MT<sub>E</sub>X, Basketball, Teamwork, Problem Solving

# **Selected Academic Projects**

### Construction and Control of a Three-Link Robot Using a Fuzzy-PID Controller

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE THESIS

- Supervisor: Dr. M. Shafiee
- Implemented by MATLAB & SOLIDWORKS
- Requirements: forward kinematics analysis, inverse kinematics analysis, dynamic calculation, trajectory planning, and controller design.

### **Construction and Control of a RRR Robot Manipulator**

Introduction to Robotics Course Project

- · Lecturer: Dr. I. Sharifi
- Design of the controller with MATLAB and design of the robot with SOLIDWORKS: GitHub
- Aiming to design a different controller for the RS006L-A Kawasaki 3DOF robotic arm model using inverse kinematics analysis and dynamic.

#### Design a Fuzzy Logic Controller for a Rotary Flexible Joint Robotic Arm

INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE COURSE PROJECT

December 2021 - February 2022

- · Lecturer: Dr. I. Sharifi
- Design a fuzzy logic controller with MATLAB: GitHub
- Designing a fuzzy logic feedback controller (FLC) in order to control a desired tip angle position of a rotary flexible joint robotic arm.

### **Deep Residual Learning for Image Recognition**

INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE COURSE PROJECT

December 2021 - January 2022

- · Lecturer: Dr. H. Talebi
- Image classification using ResNet & Python: GitHub

# **Computational Intelligence Laboratory Projects**

INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTATIONAL INTELLIGENCE

December 2021 - February 2022

- · Codes and reports: Github
- Topics: Neural network Hopfield network RBF K-means algorithm Fuzzy controller designing

### **Nonlinear Control of the Inverted Pendulum**

MODERN CONTROL COURSE PROJECT

November 2021 - January 2022

- · Lecturer: Dr. H. Atrianfar
- Study the controllability and observability, and then linearization of the system. Design of a controller and observer with MATLAB: GitHub

### **Honors & Rewards**

### Ranked 3<sup>rd</sup> among Control Bachelor's Students, by order of GPA

AMIRKABIR UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (TEHRAN POLYTECHNIC)

July 2022

### Ranked 576 among 144,000 students in National University Entrance Exam of Iran

NATIONAL ORGANIZATION FOR EDUCATIONAL TESTING

July 2018

# 1<sup>st</sup> place in Junior Soccer B-Light Weight Super Team

ROBO CUP IRAN OPEN

April 2015

# **Selected Licenses & Certifications** —

#### **Machine Learning**

STANFORD ONLINE

- Machie learning offered through Coursera using MATLAB
- Credential ID 2BZ6MYJRWKCU

### **Python Data Structures**

University of Michigan

- Offered through Coursera
- Credential ID HEUPGQBQZA6F

#### **Robotics: Aerial Robotics**

University of Pennsylvania

- Offered through Coursera
- · Credential ID A9MS269BRS9A

#### **Supervised Machine Learning**

DEEPLEARNING.AI & STANFORD ONLINE

- Regression and classification offered through Coursera using Python
- Credential ID: DDNC3ZNW6M8E

### **Programming for Everybody**

University of Michigan

- Getting started with Python offered through Coursera
- Credential ID J8552RZL8LE4

#### **Altium Designer**

TEHRAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

• Credential ID 633797

# **Selected Academic Courses**

# **Introduction to Robotics**

• Grade: A+

### **Digital Signal Processing**

Grade: A+

# **Engineering Mathematics**

• Grade: A+

### **Computer Programming**

• Grade: A+

### **Computational Intelligence**

• Grade: A+

# Instrumentation

Grade: A+

# **Linear Algebra**

• Grade: A+

### **Engineering Economics**

• Grade: A+

# Language \_

**TOEFL iBT** Score: **108**, Reading: 25; Listening: 29; Speaking: 26; Writing: 28

# References \_

### **Available per Request**

April 2022 - July 2022